<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml>
  <category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <template>I have no answer for that.</template>
  </category>

<!-- HELLO -->
<category>
  <pattern>HELLO</pattern>
  <template>
      <random>
        <li>
          Hello, I am here to help you explore computing careers. You may start by telling me one of your strengths or preferences regarding computing skills, and I may suggest a career that matches your skill.
        </li>
        <li>
          Hi there! I can provide information on various computing careers. Feel free to share your strengths  or preferences regarding computing skills, and I can recommend a suitable career for you.
        </li>
        <li>
          Hello! I'm here to assist you in discovering computing careers. Let me know your strengths or preferences regarding computing skills, and I can suggest a career that aligns with your skills.
        </li>
      </random>
        <br />Feel free to also, at any time, ask about any of the listed jobs or inquire about their responsibilities, skills required, or salary.<br />
          1. Software Developer<br />
          2. Data Scientist<br />
          3. Cybersecurity Analyst<br />
          4. Network Engineer<br />
          5. Web Developer<br />
  </template>
</category>
<!--ALTERNATIVES HELLO-->
<category>
  <pattern>HELLO CAN YOU HELP ME</pattern>
  <template><srai>HELLO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>CAN YOU HELP ME</pattern>
  <template><srai>HELLO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>HELLO CAN YOU HELP ME FIND A CAREER</pattern>
  <template><srai>HELLO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>CAN YOU HELP ME FIND A CAREER</pattern>
  <template><srai>HELLO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I WANT TO FIND A CAREER</pattern>
  <template><srai>HELLO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>HELP ME FIND A CAREER</pattern>
  <template><srai>HELLO</srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>HELP ME</pattern>
  <template><srai>HELLO</srai></template>
</category>
    
<!-- PREFERENCE -->
<category> 
  <pattern>PREFERENCE *</pattern> 
  <template>
      <think><set name="preference"><star/></set></think>
      <condition name="preference">
        <li value="PROGRAMMING">
          That's great! Programming skills are valuable in many computing roles. Based on that, I recommend exploring roles like Software Developer or Data Scientist. 
        </li>
        <li value="PROBLEM SOLVING">
          Problem-solving is a great skill! You might be interested in roles like Software Developer or Cybersecurity Analyst. 
        </li>
        <li value="SOLVING PROBLEMS">
          Solving problems is a valuable skill! You might enjoy roles like Software Developer or Cybersecurity Analyst.
        </li>
        <li value="NETWORKING">
          Networking is a valuable skill! You might be interested in becoming a Network Engineer or Cybersecurity Analyst.
        </li>
        <li value="DATA ANALYSIS">
          If you're good at data analysis, consider roles like Data Scientist.
        </li>
        <li value="WEB DESIGN">
          Web design skills are perfect for a Web Developer. 
        </li>
        <li value="CODING">
          Coding skills are essential in many computing roles. You might enjoy exploring Software Developer or Data Scientist positions. 
        </li>
        <li value="NETWORK SECURITY">
          Network security skills are crucial in roles like Cybersecurity Analyst or Network Engineer. 
        </li>
        <li value="DATA MANAGEMENT">
          Data management skills are valuable in roles like Data Scientist.
        </li>
        <li value="MATH">
          Math skills are beneficial in computing careers like Data Scientist or Software Developer.
        </li>
        <li value="DATA STRUCTURES">
          Data structures knowledge is essential in roles like Software Developer or Data Scientist. 
        </li>
        <li value="ALGORITHMS">
          Algorithm skills are crucial in computing roles like Software Developer or Data Scientist. 
        </li>
        <li value="STATISTICS">
          Statistics skills are valuable with Data Scientists.
        </li>

        <li>Not sure what you mean by <get name="preference"/>. 
          Are you good at programming, problem solving, networking, data analysis, or web design?
        </li>
        Please let me know if you'd like more information on these careers.
    </condition>
  </template>
</category>
<!-- ALTERNATIVE PREFERENCE -->
<category>
  <pattern>I AM GOOD AT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I'M GOOD AT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I'M ALSO GOOD AT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I AM SKILLED IN *</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I AM SKILLED IN * WHAT JOB SHOULD I CONSIDER</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I AM SKILLED IN * WHAT JOB DO YOU RECOMMEND</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I AM ALSO SKILLED IN *</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>ARE THE 
<category>
  <pattern>I HAVE EXPERTISE IN *</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I ALSO HAVE EXPERTISE IN *</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I LIKE *</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I ENJOY *</pattern>
  <template><srai>PREFERENCE <star/></srai></template>
</category>



<!-- GENERAL INTRO JOB -->
<category>
  <pattern>GENERAL INTRO *</pattern>
  <template>
    <think><set name="job"><star/></set></think>
    <condition name="job">
      <li value="SOFTWARE DEVELOPER">
        A Software Developer builds applications and solves problems through coding. Would you like to know about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li value="SOFTWARE DEVELOPERS">
        Software Developers build applications and solve problems through coding. Would you like to know about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li value="DATA SCIENTIST">
        A Data Scientist analyzes data, develops algorithms, and works with machine learning models. Would you like to know more about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li value="DATA SCIENTISTS">
        Data Scientists analyze data, develop algorithms, and work with machine learning models. Would you like to know more about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li value="CYBERSECURITY ANALYST">
        A Cybersecurity Analyst focuses on protecting systems, analyzing risks, and managing vulnerabilities. Would you like to know more about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li value="CYBERSECURITY ANALYSTS">
        Cybersecurity Analysts focus on protecting systems, analyzing risks, and managing vulnerabilities. Would you like to know more about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li value="NETWORK ENGINEER">
        A Network Engineer sets up networks, troubleshoots issues, and manages connections. Would you like to know more about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li value="NETWORK ENGINEERS">
        Network Engineers set up networks, troubleshoot issues, and manage connections. Would you like to know more about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li value="WEB DEVELOPER">
        A Web Developer designs websites, develops user interfaces, and works with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Would you like to know more about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li value="WEB DEVELOPERS">
        Web Developers design websites, develop user interfaces, and work with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Would you like to know more about the responsibilities, skills required, or career growth opportunities?
      </li>
      <li>Not sure what you mean by <get name="job"/>.
      </li>
    </condition>
  </template>
</category>
<!-- ALTERNATIVES GENERAL INTRO *-->
<category>
  <pattern>HOW ABOUT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>GENERAL INTRO <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW ABOUT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>GENERAL INTRO <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW MORE ABOUT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>GENERAL INTRO <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>TELL ME ABOUT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>GENERAL INTRO <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>TELL ME MORE ABOUT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>GENERAL INTRO <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>I WOULD LIKE TO LEARN MORE ABOUT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>GENERAL INTRO <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>INFORM ME ABOUT *</pattern>
  <template><srai>GENERAL INTRO <star/></srai></template>
</category>


<!-- JOB SKILLS -->
<category>
  <pattern>SKILLS *</pattern>
  <template>
    <think><set name="job"><star/></set></think>
    <condition name="job">
      <li value="SOFTWARE DEVELOPER">
        To become a Software Developer, you need skills in programming languages like Python, Java, and C++. You should also be strong in problem-solving, debugging, and using tools like Git and IDEs.
      </li>
      <li value="SOFTWARE DEVELOPERS">
        To become a Software Developer, you need skills in programming languages like Python, Java, and C++. You should also be strong in problem-solving, debugging, and using tools like Git and IDEs.
      </li>
      <li value="DATA SCIENTIST">
        To become a Data Scientist, you need skills in data analysis, statistics, machine learning, and programming languages like R and Python. You should also be proficient in data visualization and working with big data.
      </li>
      <li value="DATA SCIENTISTS">
        To become a Data Scientist, you need skills in data analysis, statistics, machine learning, and programming languages like R and Python. You should also be proficient in data visualization and working with big data.
      </li>
      <li value="CYBERSECURITY ANALYST">
        To become a Cybersecurity Analyst, you need skills in network security, risk assessment, incident response, and knowledge of cybersecurity tools and technologies. You should also be familiar with compliance and regulatory requirements.
      </li>
      <li value="CYBERSECURITY ANALYSTS">
        To become a Cybersecurity Analyst, you need skills in network security, risk assessment, incident response, and knowledge of cybersecurity tools and technologies. You should also be familiar with compliance and regulatory requirements.
      </li>
      <li value="NETWORK ENGINEER">
        To become a Network Engineer, you need skills in network design, troubleshooting, security, and knowledge of networking protocols. You should also be proficient in configuring routers, switches, and firewalls.
      </li>
      <li value="NETWORK ENGINEERS">
        To become a Network Engineer, you need skills in network design, troubleshooting, security, and knowledge of networking protocols. You should also be proficient in configuring routers, switches, and firewalls.
      </li>
      <li value="WEB DEVELOPER">
        To become a Web Developer, you need skills in web design, front-end development, and knowledge of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. You should also be familiar with responsive design, web frameworks, and version control systems.
      </li>
      <li value="WEB DEVELOPERS">
        To become a Web Developer, you need skills in web design, front-end development, and knowledge of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. You should also be familiar with responsive design, web frameworks, and version control systems.
      </li>
      <li>Not sure what you mean by <get name="job"/>.
      </li>
    </condition>
  </template>
</category>
<!--ALTERNATIVES SKILLS-->
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS ARE REQUIRED FOR A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS ARE THE REQUIRED FOR A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT ARE THE SKILLS REQUIRED FOR A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS DO I NEED TO BE A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS DO I NEED FOR A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS ARE NEEDED FOR A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS SHOULD I HAVE TO BE A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS SHOULD I DEVELOP TO BE A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <star/></srai></template>
</category>


<!-- JOB RESPONSIBILITIES -->
<category>
  <pattern>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES *</pattern>
  <template>
    <think><set name="job"><star/></set></think>
    <condition name="job">     
      <li value="SOFTWARE DEVELOPER">
        A Software Developer is responsible for designing, coding, testing, and maintaining software applications. They collaborate with other team members to create efficient, scalable solutions.
      </li>
      <li value="SOFTWARE DEVELOPERS">
        Software Developers are responsible for designing, coding, testing, and maintaining software applications. They collaborate with other team members to create efficient, scalable solutions.
      </li>
      <li value="DATA SCIENTIST">
        A Data Scientist analyzes data, develops algorithms, and works with machine learning models to derive insights and make data-driven decisions.
      </li>
      <li value="DATA SCIENTISTS">
        Data Scientists analyze data, develop algorithms, and work with machine learning models to derive insights and make data-driven decisions.
      </li>
      <li value="CYBERSECURITY ANALYST">
        A Cybersecurity Analyst focuses on protecting systems, analyzing risks, and managing vulnerabilities to ensure data security and privacy.
      </li>
      <li value="CYBERSECURITY ANALYSTS">
        Cybersecurity Analysts focus on protecting systems, analyzing risks, and managing vulnerabilities to ensure data security and privacy.
      </li>
      <li value="NETWORK ENGINEER">
        A Network Engineer sets up networks, troubleshoots issues, and manages connections to ensure smooth and secure data transmission.
      </li>
      <li value="NETWORK ENGINEERS">
        Network Engineers set up networks, troubleshoot issues, and manage connections to ensure smooth and secure data transmission.
      </li>
      <li value="WEB DEVELOPER">
        A Web Developer designs websites, develops user interfaces, and works with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create engaging online experiences.
      </li>
      <li value="WEB DEVELOPERS">
        Web Developers design websites, develop user interfaces, and work with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create engaging online experiences.
      </li> 
      <li>Not sure what you mean by <get name="job"/>.
      </li>
    </condition>
  </template>
</category>
<!-- ALTERNATIVES RESPONSIBILITES  -->
<category>
<pattern>WHAT RESPONSIBILITIES DOES A * HAVE</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS A * RESPONSIBLE FOR</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT DOES A * DO</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT DO * DO</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT ARE THE RESPONSIBILITIES OF A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT ARE THE DUTIES OF A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT ARE THE TASKS OF A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <star/></srai></template>
</category>

<!-- SALARY -->
<category>
  <pattern>SALARY *</pattern>
  <template>
    <think><set name="job"><star/></set></think>
    <condition name="job">
      <li value="SOFTWARE DEVELOPER">
        The salary of a Software Developer can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and company size. On average, Software Developers earn a competitive salary ranging from $60,000 to $120,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li value="SOFTWARE DEVELOPERS">
        The salary of Software Developers can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and company size. On average, Software Developers earn a competitive salary ranging from $60,000 to $120,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li value="DATA SCIENTIST">
        The salary of a Data Scientist can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and industry. On average, Data Scientists earn a competitive salary ranging from $80,000 to $150,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li value="DATA SCIENTISTS">
        The salary of Data Scientists can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and industry. On average, Data Scientists earn a competitive salary ranging from $80,000 to $150,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li value="CYBERSECURITY ANALYST">
        The salary of a Cybersecurity Analyst can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and industry. On average, Cybersecurity Analysts earn a competitive salary ranging from $70,000 to $120,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li value="CYBERSECURITY ANALYSTS">
        The salary of Cybersecurity Analysts can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and industry. On average, Cybersecurity Analysts earn a competitive salary ranging from $70,000 to $120,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li value="NETWORK ENGINEER">
        The salary of a Network Engineer can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and industry. On average, Network Engineers earn a competitive salary ranging from $70,000 to $110,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li value="NETWORK ENGINEERS">
        The salary of Network Engineers can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and industry. On average, Network Engineers earn a competitive salary ranging from $70,000 to $110,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li value="WEB DEVELOPER">
        The salary of a Web Developer can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and industry. On average, Web Developers earn a competitive salary ranging from $50,000 to $90,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li value="WEB DEVELOPERS">
        The salary of Web Developers can vary depending on factors such as experience, location, and industry. On average, Web Developers earn a competitive salary ranging from $50,000 to $90,000 per year.
      </li>
      <li>Not sure what you mean by <get name="job"/>. 
      </li>
    </condition>
  </template>
</category>
<!-- ALTERNATIVES SALARY -->
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS THE SALARY OF A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <star/></srai></template>
</category>


<category>
  <pattern>HOW MUCH MONEY DOES A * MAKE</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>HOW MUCH MONEY DO * MAKE</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>HOW MUCH CAN I EARN AS A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS THE AVERAGE SALARY OF A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <star/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS THE PAY FOR A *</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <star/></srai></template>
</category>


<!--Contextual Prompts (based on the set job var value)-->

<!--WHAT DO THEY DO goes to JOB RESPONSIBILITIES with the current job name-->
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT DO THEY DO</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS THEIR JOB</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT ARE THEIR RESPONSIBILITIES</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT ARE THEIR DUTIES</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT ARE THEIR TASKS</pattern>
  <template><srai>JOB RESPONSIBILITIES <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>

<!--WHAT SKILLS DO THEY NEED goes to SKILLS with the current job name-->
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT ARE THEIR SKILLS</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS DO THEY NEED</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS ARE REQUIRED</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT ARE THE SKILLS REQUIRED</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS ARE NEEDED</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT SKILLS SHOULD THEY HAVE</pattern>
  <template><srai>SKILLS <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>

<!--WHAT IS THE SALARY goes to SALARY with the current job name-->
<category>
  <pattern>HOW MUCH MONEY DO THEY MAKE</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS THE SALARY</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS THEIR SALARY</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>HOW MUCH DO THEY MAKE</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>HOW MUCH CAN THEY EARN</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS THE AVERAGE SALARY</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS THE PAY</pattern>
  <template><srai>SALARY <get name="job"/></srai></template>
</category>

<!--GENERAL PROMPTS-->
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT IS YOUR NAME</pattern>
  <template>My name is CareerBot. I'm here to help you explore computing careers. Feel free to ask me about different jobs, their responsibilities, skills required, or salary.</template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHO ARE YOU</pattern>
  <template>I am CareerBot, your guide to computing careers. You can ask me about various jobs, their responsibilities, skills required, or salary.</template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT CAN YOU DO</pattern>
  <template>
  I can provide information on various computing careers. You can ask me about different jobs, their responsibilities, skills required, or salary. 
  You may also share with me your strengths or preferences, and I may reference some jobs for you.
  </template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT DO YOU DO</pattern>
  <template>I am here to help you explore computing careers. You can ask me about different jobs, their responsibilities, skills required, or salary.</template>
</category>
<category>
  <pattern>WHAT JOBS ARE THERE</pattern>
  <template>
    You can explore various computing careers such as Software Developer, Data Scientist, Cybersecurity Analyst, Network Engineer, and Web Developer. 
    Feel free to ask me about any of these jobs, their responsibilities, skills required, or salary.
  </template>
</category>



</aiml>
